<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Answer Jar]]></title><description><![CDATA[Satisfying the internet's inquiring minds.]]></description><link>https://answerjar.com</link><image><url>https://answerjar.com/logos/logo-512.png</url><title>Answer Jar</title><link>https://answerjar.com</link></image><generator>GatsbyJS Advanced Starter</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 04:44:14 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://answerjar.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><copyright><![CDATA[Copyright © 2020. Set the Curve]]></copyright><item><title><![CDATA[Can a team get a touchback if the ball does not touch the ground in college football?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Yes, it is possible for a team to get a touchback even if the ball doesn't touch the ground.  To explain why, it is first necessary to…]]></description><link>https://answerjar.com/touchback-not-touching-ground-cfb</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://answerjar.com/touchback-not-touching-ground-cfb</guid><category><![CDATA[College Football]]></category><category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Yes, it is possible for a team to get a touchback even if the ball doesn&apos;t touch the ground.  To explain why, it is first necessary to define what exactly a touchback is.  The NCAA college football rulebook gives the following two conditions for when a touchback should be declared:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ARTICLE 1. It is a touchback when:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. The ball becomes dead out of bounds behind a goal line, except from an incomplete forward pass, or becomes dead in the possession of a player on, above or behind his own goal line and the attacking team is responsible for the ball being there (Rules 7-2-4-c) (A.R. 7-2-4-I, A.R. 8-6-1-I-III).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. A kick becomes dead by rule behind the defending team’s goal line and the attacking team is responsible for the ball being there (Exception: Rule 8-4-2-b) (A.R. 6-3-4-III). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From article 1a, if an attacking team causes the ball to go into the endzone (on, above, or behind the goal line), and a player gains possession there, it is a touchback.  Say, for example, the attacking team punts the ball into the endzone and a defending player there successfully catches the ball and chooses not to run it out.  That would be a touchback without the ball ever hitting the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is certainly possible for a touchback to occur when the ball &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; hit the ground.  Article 1b covers such a scenario (for example, the attacking team punting the ball, which rolls into the endzone and comes to rest dead there).  But touching the ground is not necessary for a touchback to occur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sources&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#sources&quot; aria-label=&quot;sources permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Sources:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncaapublications.com/productdownloads/FR20.pdf&quot;&gt;College Football Rulebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded><author></author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why are old pictures of atoms in science textbooks wrong?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Representations of atoms in older science textbooks are incorrect because they do not take account later developments in quantum mechanics…]]></description><link>https://answerjar.com/old-atom-pictures-science-textbooks-wrong</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://answerjar.com/old-atom-pictures-science-textbooks-wrong</guid><category><![CDATA[Science]]></category><category><![CDATA[Physics]]></category><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Representations of atoms in older science textbooks are incorrect because they do not take account later developments in quantum mechanics which enhanced our understanding of atomic behavior.  Previously, scientists believed that electrons orbited the nucleus of the atom much in the same way that the moon orbits the earth.  In other words, two spheres with definite position, with one moving in circles around the other due to centripetal force (gravity in the planetary case, electromagnetism in the atomic case).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, one of the biggest findings of quantum mechanics is that particles exhibit wave-like behavior.  They spread out through space according to their wave function (which evolves over time according to the Schrödinger wave equation), only taking on a definite position in space when they are observed.  From the wave function, it is possible to determine the probability of finding a particle (the electron) in a given location, but without directly observing it and collapsing the wave function it is impossible to say for certain where it is (unlike in the classical model of the atom).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this new understanding of nature (and the mathematics that accompanied it), scientists updated their model of the atom to more accurately describe reality.  Electrons exist in orbital shells, which give the probability of finding the electron in given positions.  Additionally, much in the same way that a guitar string can only vibrate at certain frequencies based on its length, an electron-wave can only exist in certain quantized energy states based on the potential energy well created by the nucleus of the atom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sources&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#sources&quot; aria-label=&quot;sources permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Sources:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chem.libretexts.org/Bookshelves/General_Chemistry/Book%3A_Chem1_(Lower)/05%3A_Atoms_and_the_Periodic_Table/5.05%3A_The_Quantum_Atom&quot;&gt;The Quantum Atom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded><author></author></item><item><title><![CDATA[What is the definition of a non-Power Five (non-P5) college football team?]]></title><description><![CDATA[In college football (and college athletics in general), teams are self-organized into conferences which determine the schedule the team…]]></description><link>https://answerjar.com/non-power-five-college-football-team</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://answerjar.com/non-power-five-college-football-team</guid><category><![CDATA[College Football]]></category><category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In college football (and college athletics in general), teams are self-organized into conferences which determine the schedule the team plays and what revenue they are able to receive for their university. The term &quot;Power Five (P5)&quot; is used to denote a group of five conferences which have historically been the strongest in terms of team performance and recruiting.  These conferences are the Atlantic Coast Conference (ACC), the Southeastern Conference (SEC), the Big Ten (B1G), the Big Twelve (XII), and the Pacific Twelve (PAC-12).  Teams which are members of these conferences are known as &quot;Power Five&quot; (or P5) teams.  Usually this designation comes with a certain level prestige, as the level of competition played over the course of the season is typically considered more challenging than for other non-P5 teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversely, non-Power Five teams are colloquially known as &quot;Group of Five&quot; (G5) teams.  They are teams belonging to one of the Group of Five of conferences: the American Conference, Conference USA, the Mid-American Conference (MAC), the Mountain West Conference, and the Sun Belt Conference.  Popularly, these schools have a reputation for having easier playing schedules (whether justified or not).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few exceptions which don&apos;t fall neatly into the P5/G5 divide, however.  Teams such as BYU and Notre Dame have resisted joining a conference in the past and retain &quot;Independent&quot; status, which affords them more flexibility in creating their own schedules and rules.  Due to the historical strength of their football programs, they are typically not referred to as non-P5 teams, even though they do not play in a P5 conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sources&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#sources&quot; aria-label=&quot;sources permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Sources:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.espn.com/college-football/story/_/page/weeklyscenario100419/which-teams-reach-group-5-college-football-playoff&quot;&gt;Which teams would reach a Group of 5 College Football Playoff?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded><author></author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Can a college football player declare for the NFL draft and still play in their bowl game?]]></title><description><![CDATA[In short, yes, a college football player can declare for the NFL draft and still play in their college team's bowl game.   The NFL lists…]]></description><link>https://answerjar.com/college-football-player-bowl-game-nfl</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://answerjar.com/college-football-player-bowl-game-nfl</guid><category><![CDATA[College Football]]></category><category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In short, yes, a college football player can declare for the NFL draft and still play in their college team&apos;s bowl game.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NFL lists player eligibility requirements on their website.  Of particular note is the following section:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be eligible for the draft, players must have been out of high school for at least three years and must have used up their college eligibility before the start of the next college football season. Underclassmen and players who have graduated before using all their college eligibility may request the league’s approval to enter the draft early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for a player to enter the NFL draft early, they have to receive approval from the league.  The NFL further clarifies the timetable for doing so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Player Personnel staff also review all of the applications submitted by players who want to enter the draft early. &lt;strong&gt;Underclassmen have until seven days following the NCAA National Championship Game to declare their intentions to do so.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even when declaring early, players have seven days after the Championship Bowl Game to do so (the last bowl of the season).  Players may choose to sit out their bowl games for safety reasons, but there is nothing requiring them to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sources&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#sources&quot; aria-label=&quot;sources permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Sources:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://operations.nfl.com/the-players/the-nfl-draft/the-rules-of-the-draft/&quot;&gt;NFL Official Rules of the Draft&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded><author></author></item><item><title><![CDATA[What does D2D mean in basketball?]]></title><description><![CDATA[The acronym "D2D", as used in basketball and other sports, stands for "Day-to-Day".  It is a representation of a player's injury status.  If…]]></description><link>https://answerjar.com/d-2-d-in-basketball</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://answerjar.com/d-2-d-in-basketball</guid><category><![CDATA[Basketball]]></category><category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The acronym &quot;D2D&quot;, as used in basketball and other sports, stands for &quot;Day-to-Day&quot;.  It is a representation of a player&apos;s injury status.  If a player is listed as &quot;D2D&quot; on the injury report, it means they are recovering from an injury and are close to returning to the team&apos;s game time lineup.  In other words, their ability to play is being evaluated on a &quot;day-to-day&quot; basis (as opposed to being listed as &quot;Out&quot;, where there is no need to consistently check their ability to return).&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded><author></author></item><item><title><![CDATA[What does GC represent in college football?]]></title><description><![CDATA[The acronym "GC" in college football stands for "Game Control".  The College Football Playoff selection committee has acknowledged this as a…]]></description><link>https://answerjar.com/gc-college-football</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://answerjar.com/gc-college-football</guid><category><![CDATA[College Football]]></category><category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The acronym &quot;GC&quot; in college football stands for &quot;Game Control&quot;.  The College Football Playoff selection committee has acknowledged this as a &apos;somewhat subjective&apos; tool used for picking the final four playoff teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ESPN, for its part, has created a ranking system for game control, although the CFP selection committee has not formalized their metric as something they officially use.  ESPN explains that this number is a ranking which reflects the chance that an average Top 25 team would control games from start to end the way this team did, given the schedule.  They clarify further:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With play-by-play data for all games, we can go much more in depth and look at each team’s chances of winning on every play of every game based on the score, time remaining and other parts of the game situation. By looking at those chances across all plays, we can calculate a team’s average in-game win probability, a measure of how exactly it went about winning (or losing) throughout games that goes beyond just the 12 or 13 final results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To try to distill this to simpler terms, teams with a high game control statistic would have a high win probability from start-to-finish in their games.  Qualitatively, this can be looked at as the outcome never being &quot;in doubt&quot;.  Whereas a team with low game control would have a low probability of winning for most of the game.  Think of games where a miraculous last-minute series of touchdowns pushes them over the edge to win.  It could be argued that these types of games do not go as far in proving the true strength of the victorious team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sources&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#sources&quot; aria-label=&quot;sources permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Sources:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.espn.com/college-football/playoffPicture&quot;&gt;ESPN Playoff Picture Ranking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.espn.com/blog/statsinfo/post/_/id/96761/determining-the-most-deserving-teams&quot;&gt;Determining the &apos;most deserving&apos; teams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbssports.com/college-football/news/murky-game-control-becomes-a-tool-for-playoff-committee/&quot;&gt;Murky &apos;Game Control&apos; becomes a tool for playoff committee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded><author></author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Did Pat Sajak play professional basketball?]]></title><description><![CDATA[No, Pat Sajak never played professional basketball.  He is the long-running host of the popular game show Wheel of Fortune.   His biography…]]></description><link>https://answerjar.com/pat-sajak-pro-basketball</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://answerjar.com/pat-sajak-pro-basketball</guid><category><![CDATA[Basketball]]></category><category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;No, Pat Sajak never played professional basketball.  He is the long-running host of the popular game show Wheel of Fortune.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His biography on Wheel of Fortune&apos;s official website states that before joining the show, he worked in broadcasting, news, and weather in various cities such as Chicago, Nashville, and Los Angeles.  He also spent a year and a half with the Armed Forces Radio in Vietnam.  But there is no mention of basketball (professional or otherwise).  A search of the Basketball Reference NBA archives confirms this, with no mention of a player named Pat Sajak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sources&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#sources&quot; aria-label=&quot;sources permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Sources:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wheeloffortune.com/more/the-show&quot;&gt;Pat Sajak Biography on Wheel of Fortune Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.basketball-reference.com/search/search.fcgi?search=Pat+Sajak&quot;&gt;Basketball Reference Search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded><author></author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Can a football team not in any conference play in the College Football Playoffs?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Yes, a team which is not a member of any conference can play in the College Football Playoffs, as there are no conference requirements for…]]></description><link>https://answerjar.com/no-conference-team-college-playoffs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://answerjar.com/no-conference-team-college-playoffs</guid><category><![CDATA[College Football]]></category><category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Yes, a team which is not a member of any conference can play in the College Football Playoffs, as there are no conference requirements for being selected by the selection committee.  In fact, in 2018, Notre Dame played in the College Football Playoffs as a team without a conference (Independent status).  Additionally, in 2020, Notre Dame was selected for the playoffs again, but during this season they were a one-season member of the Atlantic Coast Conference (due to special COVID-19 considerations).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there is no requirement to play in a conference, it can prove beneficial in helping a team achieve a higher ranking and end up in the top 4 teams which are ultimately selected for the playoffs.  The selection committee lists the following under &quot;What criteria does the selection committee use to rank the teams?&quot; in the FAQs section on their website:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The selection committee ranks the teams based on the members’ evaluation of the teams’ performance on the field, using conference championships won, strength of schedule, head-to-head results and comparison of results against common opponents to decide among teams that are comparable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As playing in a conference affords teams a chance to compete for a conference championship, it provides teams with an opportunity at achieving one of the accomplishments used by the committee as justification for ranking teams higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sources&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#sources&quot; aria-label=&quot;sources permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Sources:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.espn.com/college-football/boxscore?gameId=401032079&quot;&gt;2018 CFP Semifinal Box Score&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://collegefootballplayoff.com/sports/2017/9/20/selection-committee-faq.aspx&quot;&gt;Selection Committee FAQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded><author></author></item></channel></rss>