<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Answer Jar]]></title><description><![CDATA[Satisfying the internet's inquiring minds.]]></description><link>https://answerjar.com</link><image><url>https://answerjar.com/logos/logo-512.png</url><title>Answer Jar</title><link>https://answerjar.com</link></image><generator>GatsbyJS Advanced Starter</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 07:45:33 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://answerjar.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><copyright><![CDATA[Copyright © 2020. Set the Curve]]></copyright><item><title><![CDATA[Can a college football player declare for the NFL draft and still play in their bowl game?]]></title><description><![CDATA[In short, yes, a college football player can declare for the NFL draft and still play in their college team's bowl game.   The NFL lists…]]></description><link>https://answerjar.com/college-football-player-bowl-game-nfl</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://answerjar.com/college-football-player-bowl-game-nfl</guid><category><![CDATA[College Football]]></category><category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In short, yes, a college football player can declare for the NFL draft and still play in their college team&apos;s bowl game.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NFL lists player eligibility requirements on their website.  Of particular note is the following section:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be eligible for the draft, players must have been out of high school for at least three years and must have used up their college eligibility before the start of the next college football season. Underclassmen and players who have graduated before using all their college eligibility may request the league’s approval to enter the draft early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for a player to enter the NFL draft early, they have to receive approval from the league.  The NFL further clarifies the timetable for doing so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Player Personnel staff also review all of the applications submitted by players who want to enter the draft early. &lt;strong&gt;Underclassmen have until seven days following the NCAA National Championship Game to declare their intentions to do so.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even when declaring early, players have seven days after the Championship Bowl Game to do so (the last bowl of the season).  Players may choose to sit out their bowl games for safety reasons, but there is nothing requiring them to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sources&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#sources&quot; aria-label=&quot;sources permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Sources:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://operations.nfl.com/the-players/the-nfl-draft/the-rules-of-the-draft/&quot;&gt;NFL Official Rules of the Draft&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded><author></author></item><item><title><![CDATA[What does D2D mean in basketball?]]></title><description><![CDATA[The acronym "D2D", as used in basketball and other sports, stands for "Day-to-Day".  It is a representation of a player's injury status.  If…]]></description><link>https://answerjar.com/d-2-d-in-basketball</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://answerjar.com/d-2-d-in-basketball</guid><category><![CDATA[Basketball]]></category><category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The acronym &quot;D2D&quot;, as used in basketball and other sports, stands for &quot;Day-to-Day&quot;.  It is a representation of a player&apos;s injury status.  If a player is listed as &quot;D2D&quot; on the injury report, it means they are recovering from an injury and are close to returning to the team&apos;s game time lineup.  In other words, their ability to play is being evaluated on a &quot;day-to-day&quot; basis (as opposed to being listed as &quot;Out&quot;, where there is no need to consistently check their ability to return).&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded><author></author></item><item><title><![CDATA[What does GC represent in college football?]]></title><description><![CDATA[The acronym "GC" in college football stands for "Game Control".  The College Football Playoff selection committee has acknowledged this as a…]]></description><link>https://answerjar.com/gc-college-football</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://answerjar.com/gc-college-football</guid><category><![CDATA[College Football]]></category><category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The acronym &quot;GC&quot; in college football stands for &quot;Game Control&quot;.  The College Football Playoff selection committee has acknowledged this as a &apos;somewhat subjective&apos; tool used for picking the final four playoff teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ESPN, for its part, has created a ranking system for game control, although the CFP selection committee has not formalized their metric as something they officially use.  ESPN explains that this number is a ranking which reflects the chance that an average Top 25 team would control games from start to end the way this team did, given the schedule.  They clarify further:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With play-by-play data for all games, we can go much more in depth and look at each team’s chances of winning on every play of every game based on the score, time remaining and other parts of the game situation. By looking at those chances across all plays, we can calculate a team’s average in-game win probability, a measure of how exactly it went about winning (or losing) throughout games that goes beyond just the 12 or 13 final results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To try to distill this to simpler terms, teams with a high game control statistic would have a high win probability from start-to-finish in their games.  Qualitatively, this can be looked at as the outcome never being &quot;in doubt&quot;.  Whereas a team with low game control would have a low probability of winning for most of the game.  Think of games where a miraculous last-minute series of touchdowns pushes them over the edge to win.  It could be argued that these types of games do not go as far in proving the true strength of the victorious team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sources&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#sources&quot; aria-label=&quot;sources permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Sources:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.espn.com/college-football/playoffPicture&quot;&gt;ESPN Playoff Picture Ranking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.espn.com/blog/statsinfo/post/_/id/96761/determining-the-most-deserving-teams&quot;&gt;Determining the &apos;most deserving&apos; teams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbssports.com/college-football/news/murky-game-control-becomes-a-tool-for-playoff-committee/&quot;&gt;Murky &apos;Game Control&apos; becomes a tool for playoff committee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded><author></author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Did Pat Sajak play professional basketball?]]></title><description><![CDATA[No, Pat Sajak never played professional basketball.  He is the long-running host of the popular game show Wheel of Fortune.   His biography…]]></description><link>https://answerjar.com/pat-sajak-pro-basketball</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://answerjar.com/pat-sajak-pro-basketball</guid><category><![CDATA[Basketball]]></category><category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;No, Pat Sajak never played professional basketball.  He is the long-running host of the popular game show Wheel of Fortune.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His biography on Wheel of Fortune&apos;s official website states that before joining the show, he worked in broadcasting, news, and weather in various cities such as Chicago, Nashville, and Los Angeles.  He also spent a year and a half with the Armed Forces Radio in Vietnam.  But there is no mention of basketball (professional or otherwise).  A search of the Basketball Reference NBA archives confirms this, with no mention of a player named Pat Sajak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sources&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#sources&quot; aria-label=&quot;sources permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Sources:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wheeloffortune.com/more/the-show&quot;&gt;Pat Sajak Biography on Wheel of Fortune Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.basketball-reference.com/search/search.fcgi?search=Pat+Sajak&quot;&gt;Basketball Reference Search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded><author></author></item></channel></rss>